you saw what she did
see to feed the machines?
Not I.
It is proven
she is the better hunter.
You have a new
survive.
Prevail.
What else matters?
Blood
is in your teeth.
Take my place behind you.
That got their attention.
Down you go.
Not bad.
Okay,
Stayed out.
These will keep.
Look out below.
We have to kill off these pulses.
I never cared for being pushed around.
Here we go again,
huh?
Thanks
you.
You're
Silas Father's guilt onto the new party.
These are different times.
We're so close, friend.
A lawyer, right?
My pop burger And I mean told me you might be heading up to see me.
Marja, Pleasure.
Hey, that spear is really something you've customised or haven't you?
I've made a change or two.
You've got an eye for weapons.
I wish.
Thies.
Bye!
Nuke Agreed with you.
I can't seem to sell scrap to a Glenn talk around here.
Everyone wants boring old bows and spears.
I like the more unusual stuff and about new Khun get unusual, like that spear our talk halls around an ice rail whore.
That weapon of a raise.
What I wouldn't give to poke around inside one of those feel the lightning on my fingers.
So let's say someone you know happened to have a weapon like a raise.
You don't see for yourself.
Of course.
Look at that.
So the coils generate the spark, but the power source isn't even bolted in.
I won't lie.
She's beautiful, but there's beautiful.
And then there's beautiful.
What we need is a storm bird.
Talent lining flows over them like water off a goose.
I've got a nice rail, just like our talks.
You want to take a look?
Are you serious?
Yes.
Yes, I'd love that.
Okay.
Eww.
Obvious design flaw.
So if I replace these
Yeah, that should.
Right.
So believe it or not, she's operating at Let's be generous, half her potential.
What's with she's Oh, Pop says all weapons or girls.
I don't think he realises it's a compliment.
Well, listen, if we had a Thunder Jaws mandibles to work with her gear's would be well and truly greased Last commission I had was a month ago.
A weapon.
That's that fire
that didn't go well.
I took this thing off.
Announcer on bandit.
You got my fortune fire back.
Well, if you took down old man and his goons for this thing.
I guess she's years now.
Why don't you finish it for me first?
Make it make her into the weapon she was supposed to be.
I'm going to need a bellow back snout.
Any Bella backs will do.
Can you handle it alone?
I think I could manage that.
So we'd parts from a storm bird and a thunder draw, and you know where to find them.
That's right.
It's gonna take some travelling, though.
A storm bird roost near the free heat.
I'll pack and meet you out there.
This will be fun.
Okay?
Hunted with me, I'll turn that weapon into your new best friend.
Second best.
So machines in their cells for their own.
I wonder what sort of challenge
here in.
I'm glad to see you, Gildon.
It means I don't have to go pry you out of a flooded Damn!
Yes!
I'm glad as well.
I heard the fires were heating up for you.
Back up the mountain, huh?
That's the plan.
I'm not sure what I can do to.
If I could do anything to
you know, one old guilty tagging along, getting your trap some damn place.
You saved my life.
You showed me kindness.
So?
So you're here.
So I'm here.
Thanks, Gilda.
Be safe.
A Loy.
And when it's done,
come tell me.
A storey for once.
Close
long notches Well stocks as you asked and our scouts watching for more frost, Close our numbers Rise!
Three more hunters have passed their trials.
But our purpose was to take back the mountain.
Now what?
Stay prepared.
Sharpen your spears.
Should we not return?
Defending The cut falls to you if our chieftain agrees with this cores.
Sounds like good advice But let's hope it doesn't come to that chieftain.
The weight of command is no small burden.
I can see that.
Hi.
I take it you haven't spoken to a rare yet.
Why should I?
This is what she wanted to return to.
Thunders Drum is rolling care.
So I should have known she would find a way to push aside my spear
after the cars you took my sister,
not Oliver came back.
What happened to our area when she was a captive of the cartoon is a shaman.
She's adept with machines, tracking them, stunning them.
The car's air used her toe.
Capture them for this son ring
where they were unleashed upon the innocent.
They made her part of their blood sport
the shame she suffered beneath their pitiless sun.
She survived.
She endured,
endured by reminding herself of the spirit, her purpose.
Now that's all she has.
Tell me what happened to the first expedition.
Rail led the way to the summit, but it was blocked by a great door.
Some kind of cauldron.
New metal.
We tried to break through, but it was unflinching.
We were exhausted.
No way forward on machines behind.
I made the call to push back.
It cost us greatly.
But to remain would have cost us everything.
I'd hoped to never subject array to that again.
What do you think?
It's beyond that door.
I do not know
that expensive metal, the dead home,
nothing sacred belongs there machines and death.
That's what the melon holds death for us or with Damon.
And if we do find the spirit, then perhaps we should put it out of its misery.
For what it's worth, I'm glad you're coming with me.
Someone has to keep it safe.
Where?
Carter,
I wish you luck.
on the mountain.
A lawyer.
This is it.
My chance to reunite with spirit, perhaps to reunite her with blue light.
It's not a chance I would have had alone.
I needed an outsider.
Someone ignorant of our ways.
But no, Not ignorant.
I Are you trying to thank me, right?
Yes, of course.
That's what you do.
Untangle knots create possibilities.
Thank you.
We're making this pilgrimage possible.
What are we gonna find up there?
Rare ruins, machines and a door like that of a cauldron.
I have faith that you can find a way through it.
A Loy for beyond.
It lies the spirit.
I know I could find her there.
No, I do not doubt that Damon has tried to hide the way.
I only wish it had not been necessary to humiliate our talk.
You were wise to let him come.
He's earned the right stubbornness stone.
But
he's had to be
war demanded it.
So have I.
What did the war do?
Tow our talk and cut away everything until only his true self remained
unyielding ice.
Nobody has more.
Sure.
Well,
he fought the cars for 1000 freezing nights, yet always rallied.
His hunters at sunrise.
It is said he endured 23 wounds in those years.
His hunter's counted them, never complains one.
Instead,
he complains that life with Mieze harder.
That's right.
What have I ever given him with struggle?
Our talk told me you were captive with car Jeff.
For a long time,
it sounded bad for our talk.
It all comes back to that.
He thinks the cars had changed me.
He did not.
They merely sharpened my focus.
When all else is lost, do you think about what's truly important spirit?
The blue light beyond?
Now that I'm chieftain have the way rack, I don't suppose I can order you to tell me about silence.
Our talk would never have presumed to grasp for a secret of the conclave, which you were not our attack.
If you have dealt with silence, you need us.
Well apparent silence came to Bonn or from the distant north.
The young shaman of the owls watch remote where rarely come south to parlay someone's with a shaman.
It was, or at least when we sent runners to ask the owls watch, they said he was.
His knowledge of the machines was beyond compare He was hungry to trade what he knew to the rest of us
didn't take him long to gain the trust of the conclave and eventually an invitation to attend.
What about you?
Did you trust him?
No,
that he impressed me.
He carried himself with poison authority.
I wanted to learn from him.
But
that was not to be.
He was granted knowledge of our most sacred meeting place.
The frozen caves of the Malmstrom.
A month's march from manure.
He met with us there, as is custom at high winter.
But when we next returned, the caves had been looted.
Relics of the Old World.
Stolen holes cut in ice and metal.
Yeah, that would be silence.
All right.
Hey, vanished with spoils.
We sent our best trackers after him.
None returned.
And let me cheque back with the hours watch.
Those who had vouched for him were gone.
As though he never existed.
Some in the conclave began to doubt.
He was even a nuke to begin with.
And what do you think?
He committed an unforgivable sacrilege.
He's unscrupulous and dangerous,
but also brilliant, skilled and knowledgeable, without equal.
Except perhaps for you.
Anyone else I would warn off, but you may be able to treat with him safely.
It hasn't been easy for you, Maria.
Getting back to this point.
It was all to hear her voice again.
Miss time.
We both will.
I'd like that.
Finally we sent
How?
I don't see a way up.
Not up through
No brother,
No,
wait.
That's not all.
Please remain
e to call upon the power of the old ones.
What was this place?
The spirit once told me that this all used to be part of its domain.
A fortress that defended humankind from terrible danger.
Fortunate
looks more like a machine.
Is that not fitting,
like often dwells.
Let's just hope that some remains here.
I'm restless.
November 21st, 2064.
It's been three years since I was last here and 12 since I was running the place.
Just stuff left.
Confused about why I'm here,
wants me to find a witch, is suspend operations for a while.
Maybe a
I don't know
from the sound of her voice was something terrifying.
I don't look into her eyes.
She's so freaked out about what else is new.
Don't I wish to look into your eyes.
Okay.
Hey, Lloyd.
Were you listening?
Memories,
messages left by the old ones.
You can hear them.
I envy you.
What did they say?
I'm not sure yet.
Here.
Up and over.
She's.
You have the drop on them.
Ready or not,
I think
not this time.
I made it.
That should do it.
You can finish your fortune.
Make a way towards you.
Space is measured.
Look.
Yes.
This way.
Forget about travelling light.
There's an overlook.
It's not.
Not much farther now.
Last we were here, we fought our way through there.
But machines overcame us.
We retreated, dropping supplies,
taking losses.
Now we must prevail.
With only two warriors in a shaman.
To protect a lawyer is no ordinary war here.
They called me.
So
go that way.
Instead.
They're machines up there, but also cover.
We could stay hidden.
For what?
All right.
Get the options.
Follow my lead
hours.
Steve Frost.
It was for
what?
I went this way years ago.
Looking for cover in case machines can problem.
I have no doubt that it is guarded.
Now
we may be able to stay in.
Stay down.
It's cools as if there's chill water running through those massive pipes.
Why
go where you go?
Okay,
right.
That's not linger any longer.
We have to.
Should have brought it cards.
Okay.
Endured every cold.
This frost
Always thiss
waste your spears.
You wear your minds start senior.
Always cold.
His deepest winter.
There's the door up ahead on refuge.
We're almost through.
No,
Technically, I can't suspend the cooling system, but I can reduce the power draw so that only completely masked by the caldera.
But mast from what?
Firebreak has always been confidential for security reasons.
But this would be excessive even for the dear departed Mr Blevins.
What could possibly have gotten me so worked up,
you know?
All right.
Is this a projector?
Maybe the show.
Holograms without focus.
Let's see if I can restore power.
Are Ataka Raya?
You might see shapes drawn from light.
Don't be alarmed.
It'll take more than light to alarm me.
Thank you for being here at everyone.
I suppose it's not every day you get to have cocktails inside an active volcano, right?
Unless you're George and I get hard, they blame him for drinking on the job.
None of this would be here without our beloved director.
Any job?
So here's to you, Teddy.
You put a cork in the Yellowstone caldera.
I say you deserve a margarita.
Everyone, I'd like to add something.
This effort would have been possible without our lead programmer.
Thank you
for bringing us
are really mastermind.
Sorry.
I'll second that Director Chow.
All right, So what's our latest number?
The current counties.
1654.
Then drink up, everyone.
Here's to 1654 more years without interruption.
It was the spirit,
the old ones.
I could only grasp some of what they said.
You were right area.
This place was built to stop something terrible.
It worked for the spirit.
I'm starting to get the door is open now.
We can get through
school.
Settled
there below
Deutsche Mountain.
New metal, dead metal.
You could not pass it before we will.
This time.
We have to.
We'll have to come through a lot of machines to get to that door more than the where I could prevail against before.
Hey, Louis will see us through onward.
Our challenge awaits.
She had a thermal plant can be suspended.
The cooling system mast.
Massive challenges solved.
So why am I so nervous about the next part
we need to do is instal Anita's mysterious software.
A conversation.
This will help.
Okay,
more machines make ready.
I think.
I think we did it.
I know a lawyer door.
Can you open it?
Find it?
Show us
songs of deeds.
But that battle, it was a verse worth seeing
The door,
Joshua.
The return of the director emeritus.
Decent Hollow title.
Jeana know that title and worst subject camera crew would die of boredom.
Whatever, Gina.
It's still the most excitement this hell cave seen in a long time.
Your standards for exciting are depressing.
Li Lo.
I'll squeeze what I can out of this.
Thanks.
You always were a little sweet on Kenny.
What?
No way.
His ears are enormous.
The signs He was too busy mooning over Anita.
I want to know what he is doing here in the first place.
It's not normal.
He helped engineer the most advanced geothermal facility in history, then rode off into the sunset.
Now he wants to cheque up on his masterwork.
Seems normal to me.
But why now?
He keeps poking around in the cooling facility and asking questions about science.
Do you think there's something wrong?
Last I checked?
There's been no deviation in any of our readings since the most recent micro quakes.
Warm.
Maybe Kenny likes taking field trips on borrowed time.
It's been 14 years.
They would have frozen those accounts by now.
Has it been that long?
Man, I'm old, not old.
Just boring.
Must have been sometime in the spring of 2047 about six months after the main facility opened, way were behind schedule, and new data indicated that an incident was close, maybe only weeks away.
I was exhausted, losing weight, barely speaking, except to give orders.
I passed by Anita in the Battery Depot.
She looked at me and friend, then pulled me into this room and kissed me.
Ah, long kiss, the best kind.
I can still remember the feel of her hand on the back of my neck after she looked at me and smiled and went back to work without saying a word.
I'll never forget that moment.
Her touch, her unspoken generosity.
After she left the project, I spent years beating myself up for not keeping her somehow every time I ran into her at a conference, I felt thrilled and lost and confused all at the same time, always hoping we might have a few drinks.
Sand well reeking bill.
It was only after I saw her on stage in a hollow and 58 accepting the Mind Challenge Award in Austin with Elizabeth Sobek presenting no less glowing and happy and fulfilled that it dawned on me that I hadn't done anything wrong at all.
I could finally see that she had what she wanted and it simply wasn't me.
Okay.
Incident Information Report.
Firebreak Project type property damage and personal injury Data Incident.
November 4th 2063.
Time of incident for 11.
Reporter Jurgen Home as official incident reporter for the Firebreak Project.
It is with great concern that I report of an incident at our facility.
Incident began from a swarm of 35 seismic events beginning on 3rd and 4th of November, about 9.6 kilometres six miles north northwest of Mammoth, Wyoming, included before, in the magnitude to range with the largest magnitude 2.4 at 409 The 4th November holographic modelling shows most quakes originating in the region Late Fault Zone.
As the project senior geoscientist, I advise this number and magnitude and seismic events is a normal outcome from fluid movement through the calderas Solicit magma reservoir, as well as changes of pressure coming in interactions between magma and supercooled fluid.
However, one can be never too careful in such an unstable environment.
Shown further in this report, The incident began when I was wakened from a loud crash in the canteen.
Fortunately, I did not have to rouse the official canteen monitor since I am that self same person.
Even while acting in my formal office, I was alarmed and feared the worst inspection of the zone showed the tragic loss of a 15 millilitres bottle of nail lacquer and deep crimson shattered on the canteen floor.
Blacker also splashed on the surroundings at an area of approximately 16 metres squared.
One chair was tipped over on its side, but happily, I had the mechanical knowledge to write it.
Without further incident.
The bottle of nail lacquer is irreparable.
Moreover, the canteen monitor suffered a cut to the left hand when picking up broken glass.
This was treated by the site first data me with supervision of the fire marshal also mean but could still get infected.
Gina Bruno was identified as the owner of the bottle of nail lacquer.
In my capacity as staff psychological observer, I conclude that she has accepted the loss of her personal item in a good fashion.
But further evaluation may be necessary.
Way will keep the remote side supervisor informed of developments in such a case.
Please find following this report my salary increase request for the coming calendar year.
Okay, I admit it.
I watched the hollow of the toast six straight times, taking in every detail and need a smile the way she giggled at her own jokes.
My clumsy hand off Desai in every time it played for a second, I felt like I was there again with her among friends savouring our success with diminishing returns.
Of course, by the sixth time, I was just staring at Anita and feeling really creepy about it.
But I can be forgiven, can't I?
It was the best night of my life.
Besides, I'm entitled to a little nostalgia.
We saved the world from fire and death, or at least suffocation by ash.
So there's that right